Inventory of the J.B. Stoutamore papers, 1905-1958
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
J.B. Stoutamore papers 1905-1958
Stoutamore, J.B.
05733
2.27 cubic ft. (4 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Papers, photographs, and artifacts concerning construction and operation of the Pathfinder Dam in Wyoming.
Biography of J.B. Stoutamore
J. B. Stoutamore was superintendent at the Pathfinder Dam in Wyoming for over twenty years, retiring in 1962. He invented an electric water gauge that was installed at the Guernsey and Alcova Dams, as well as the Pathfinder Dam.
Scope and Content
The J.B. Stoutamore papers include blueprints of the Pathfinder Dam, legal documents relating to the sale of land covered by the Pathfinder Dam and Reservoir; Bureau of Reclamation memoranda and correspondence on employee inventions and conduct (1940-1947); correspondence and tables on precipitation and water levels at the dam; a newspaper clipping about I.J. Matthews, district engineer for the North Platte Project (1946); and drawings and models for the electric water gauge invented by Stoutamore.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
Received from J.B. Stoutamore, 1975
Access Terms
United States. Bureau of Reclamation; Dams--Wyoming; Dams--Design and construction; Hydraulic engineering; Water-supply engineering; Natrona County (Wyo.); Pathfinder Dam (Wyo.); Wyoming--History--1890-1918; Wyoming--History--1919-1945; Wyoming--History--1946-; Artifacts
Places; Wyoming; Agriculture and Natural Resources; Water and Water Rights
Container List
- Series I. Papers
  - Agreements and Land Deeds - Pathfinder Dam, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of Reclamation Memoranda, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Precipitation, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clipping - Irvin J. Matthews, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - Pathfinder Dam, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Water Gauge - Drawings and Parts List, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Water Level Measurements, 1909-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II. Blueprints and Maps
  - Map of Pathfinder Reservoir, Carbon and Natrona Counties, Wyoming, Showing Lands Segregated, undated (Box 2)
  - Blueprints of Pathfinder Dam (including stairs, ladders, gates, hoists, etc.), circa 1940s (Box 4)
  - Blueprints of Electrical Liquid Elevation Gauge (invented by J.B. Stoutamore), 1946 (Box 4)
- Series III. Artifacts
  - Electric Water Gauge model, undated (Box 3)
  - Balance Valve - Type first installed at Pathfinder Dam, undated (Box 3)